- 看看那些松树  - 还有那个湖
- Look at those pine trees. - And that lake.
- 我发誓我闻到了金银花的味道  - 混合着橙花
- I swear I smell honeysuckle. - With orange blossom thrown in.
这太不可思议了，生长物和半个银河系之外的地球一模一样
It's unbelievable. Growth exactly like that of Earth half a galaxy away.
- 这样的概率有多小？- 天文数字
- What are the odds of that? - Astronomical.
这个星球的大小和年龄
The size and age of this planet
这使得它极不可能像地球一样进化
makes it highly improbable that it would evolve similarly to Earth.
那是什么东西？
What in blazes is that?
- 分析？- 某种外星金属
- Analysis? - An alien metal of some kind.
一种耐探针的合金
An alloy resistant to probe.
读数甚至无法准确测量其年龄
Readings can't even measure its age accurately.
这些符号显然是某种形式的书写
These symbols are evidently some form of writing.
- 知道它是什么吗？- 不知道，舰长
- Any theories about what it is? - Negative, Captain.
如此复杂的结构需要复杂的建筑设备
Such complex structures require sophisticated building apparatus,
通常存在于超越或等同我们的文化中
the kind usually found in cultures surpassing or equaling ours.
整个地方在生物和文化上都是一个谜
The whole place is an enigma, biologically and culturally.
最接近的生物聚集地在哪儿？
What's the nearest concentration of life-forms?
方位 117，标记 4
Bearing 117, mark 4.
我们有多少时间？
How much time do we have?
如果我们要让小行星转向这颗行星,
If we are to divert the asteroid on its way to this planet,
我们必须在30分钟内离开
we must leave within 30 minutes.
我们拖延的每一秒都会使问题复杂化，也许就是过时的解决方案了
Every second we delay compounds the problem, perhaps past solution.
你说的是30分钟
You did say 30 minutes.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
那么让我们来看看什么样的生命形式受到这种环境的保佑
Then let's find out what life-forms are blessed by this environment.
我发誓他们是美洲原住民
I'd swear they're American Indians.
他们是，我相信是纳瓦霍人，莫希干人和特拉华人的混合
They are. A mixture of Navajo, Mohican and Delaware, I believe.
所有这些都在更先进和平的部落中
All among the more advanced and peaceful tribes.
这就像发现亚特兰蒂斯一样，或香格里拉
It's like discovering Atlantis. Or Shangri-La.
在这个星球上有没有可能还有一个更先进的文明？
Is it possible there's a more evolved civilization somewhere on this planet?
一个能够建造方尖碑或开发偏转系统的人？
One capable of building that obelisk or developing a deflector system?
极不可能，传感器显示这里只有一种生命形式
Highly improbable. Sensors indicate only one type of life-form here.
我们不应该联系他们吗？告诉他们？
Shouldn't we contact them? Tell them?
告诉他们什么？一颗小行星来粉碎他们的世界？
Tell them what? That an asteroid's coming to smash their world?
太原始，无法理解太空飞行的概念
Too primitive to grasp the concept of space flight.
我们在这里的出现只会让他们感到困惑和恐惧
Our appearance here would only confuse and frighten them.
我们有工作要做，让我们回到企业号
We've got a job to do. Let's get back to the Enterprise.
- 怎么了，吉姆？- 没什么
- What's the matter, Jim? - Nothing.
这里太宁静，太简单了
It's just so peaceful. Uncomplicated.
没有问题或指挥决定
No problems or command decisions.
只有...生活
Just... living.
典型的人类对田园诗般的自然环境的反应
Typical human reaction to an idyllic natural setting.
在20世纪，我们称之为塔希提岛综合症
In the 20th Century, we referred to it as the Tahiti Syndrome.
这在压力过大的领导者类型中很常见，比如星际飞船舰长
It's common to over-pressured leader types, like starship captains.
塔希提岛综合症，让我们去照顾那颗小行星吧
The Tahiti Syndrome. Let's go take care of that asteroid.
但首先，我想再看一眼那座方尖碑
But first I want another look at that obelisk.
- 医生？- 什么事？
- Doctor? - Yes?
我建议将研究推迟到我们转移小行星之后
I suggest research be delayed until after we have diverted the asteroid.
- 柯克呼叫企业号  - 斯科提[通过无线电]：是的，长官
- Kirk to Enterprise. - SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: Yes, sir.
柯克：宇宙，最后的边疆
KIRK: Space, the final frontier.
这些是星舰企业号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务：探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
寻找新生命和新文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
史波克：舰长日志，星历4842.6
SPOCK: Captain's log, stardate 4842.6.
大副史波克指挥
First Officer Spock commanding.
无数搜索队伍和反复的感应器探测
Numerous search parties and repeated sensor probes
都没找到柯克舰长
have failed to locate Captain Kirk.
- 史波克呼叫企业号  - 斯科提[通过无线电]：请回答
- Spock to Enterprise. - SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: Come in.
- 把我们传送上去，我们要走了  - 离开？你在开玩笑吧
- Beam us up. We're leaving. - Leaving? You can't be serious.
那颗小行星几乎和月球一样大
That asteroid is almost as large as your Earth's moon.
足够远，它改道所需的角度是微小的
Far enough away, the angle necessary to divert it is minute.
但随着小行星的接近，角度变得如此之大，甚至......
But as the asteroid approaches, the angle becomes so great that even...
那颗小行星在两个月内不会到达这里！
That asteroid won't get here for two months!
如果我们及时到达偏转点，它可能根本就到不了这里
If we arrive at the deflection point in time, it may not get here at all.
- 吉姆怎么办？- 我们将小行星改道，然后搜索
- What about Jim? - We'll divert the asteroid, then search.
那可能是几个小时后，他可能快死了
That may be hours from now. He may be dying.
医生
Doctor.
假设这就是我们所处的星球，这是接近的小行星
Assume this is the planet we're on. This is the approaching asteroid.
如果我们没有及时到达那里，就不可能使它转向了
It we don't get there in time, it will become impossible to divert this.
那种情况下，这个星球上的每个人都会死，包括舰长
In that case, everyone on this planet will die, including the captain.
再等几分钟有什么关系吗？
Can a few more minutes matter?
在我解释的时间里
In the time it has taken me to explain,
小行星已经从这里移动到这里
the asteroid has moved from here to here.
我们拖延的时间越长，能让它改道的可能性就越小
The longer we delay, the less the likelihood of being able to divert it.
传送我们上去，斯科特先生
Beam us up, Mr. Scott.
柯克：我在哪儿？这是什么地方？
KIRK: Where am I? What place is this?
这些是什么？我觉得我应该知道
What are these? I feel I should know.
他们很熟悉，但又不熟悉
They're familiar, and yet unfamiliar.
我是怎么来到这里的？
How did I get here?
我是谁？试着回忆一下
Who am I? Try to remember.
[刮擦声]
[SCRATCHING]
[两人笑]
[BOTH LAUGH]
女人：等等
WOMAN: Wait.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我们是你的人民
We are your people.
我们一直在等你来找我们
We've been waiting for you to come to us.
SPOCK：舰长日志，星历4843.6
SPOCK: Captain's log, stardate 4843.6.
大副史波克指挥
First Officer Spock commanding.
我们已经在前往小行星的途中停留了几个小时
We've been en route to the asteroid for hours.
我们的耽搁使得我们必须以最大曲速前进
Our delay has made it imperative that we proceed at maximum warp
时间会超过建议的安全限度
for a period which exceeds the recommended safety margin.
不能以曲速9飞行太长时间，引擎压力太大了
I can't give you warp 9 much longer. The engines are stressed.
我们不能降低速度，我不会错过这个偏转点
We cannot reduce speed. I will not miss that deflection point.
好的，但我们正在进入更危险范围
OK. But we're moving further into the danger range.
反对已记录，斯科特先生，继续
Objection noted, Mr. Scott. Carry on.
米拉曼尼说你从神殿里向她和她的侍女现身
Miramanee said you appeared to her and her handmaiden from the temple,
正如我们的传说所预言的那样
just as our legend foretells.
我们不怀疑她的话，但现在是动荡的时期
We do not doubt her words, but these are troubled times
我们必须确定
and we must be sure.
我会尽量回答，但正如我所说，很多事情对我来说都是陌生的
I'll answer anything I can, but as I said, many things are strange to me.
他什么都不知道，他怎么能拯救我们呢？
He knows nothing. How can he save us?
打断部落长老是违反习俗的
It is against custom to interrupt a tribal elder,
甚至对于医师来说也是如此
even for the medicine chief.
当天空变暗时，言语救不了我们
Words will not save us when the skies darken.
我们必须确定，我说，他必须证明自己是神
We must be certain. I say he must prove he is a god.
自收获以来，我们的天空已经变暗了三次
Our skies have darkened three times since the harvest,
上一次最糟糕的
the last time worst of all.
我们的传说预言了这种危险
Our legend predicts such danger
并承诺把我们安置在这里的智者们
and promises that the Wise Ones who planted us here
会派遣一位神来拯救我们，一位能够唤醒神殿精神的人
will send a god to save us, one who can rouse the temple spirit,
让天空变得安静
and make the sky grow quiet.
你能做到吗？
Can you do this?
我来自神殿，正如米拉曼尼所说
I came from the temple, as Miramanee said.
这对我来说是一个开始
And it was a beginning for me.
这里
Here.
但我也是从天上来的
But I came from the sky, too.
只是我...不记得了
Only I... can't remember.
我...不记得了
I... can't remember.
萨利希，发生了一件可怕的事情
Salish, a terrible thing has happened.
男孩正在看渔网，他沉到了河底
The boy was attending the fishnets and he sank to the bottom of the river.
鲁莫很快把他提起来，但他没有动
Lumo brought him up quickly, but he doesn't move.
身体没有声音
There is no sound in the body.
眼睛里没有光
There is no light in the eyes.
- 他不会再动了  - 等一下
- He will move no more. - Wait a moment.
等
Wait.
[男孩咳嗽]
[BOY COUGHS]
- 他现在就没事了  - 我的人民很感激
- He'll be all right now. - My people are grateful.
这是一个简单的技术，可以追溯到很久以前...
It's a simple technique. Goes way back...
很久以前...
Way back...
只有神才能给死人注入生命
Only a god can breathe life into the dead.
你还在质疑吗？
Do you still question?
给他医学徽章
Give him the medicine badge.
契科夫：离偏转点不足7
CHEKOV: Deflection point minus seven.
- 史波克：全功率  - 继电器将拒绝过载
- SPOCK: Full power. - The relays will reject the overload.
那就手动控制
Then go to manual control.
- 我们会烧坏引擎！  - 我要全功率运行，斯科特先生
- We'll burn out the engines! - I want full power, Mr. Scott.
好吧，你们这些可爱的家伙，团结一致
All right, you lovelies. Hold together.
[引擎加速]
[ENGINES ACCELERATE]
全功率
Full power.
放大系数12，苏鲁先生
Magnification factor 12, Mr. Sulu.
契科夫：离偏转点不足4
CHEKOV: Deflection point minus 4.
全部引擎停止，保持原位
All engines stop. Hold position.
斯科提：所有的引擎都停了，长官
SCOTTY: All engines stop, sir.
- 准备启动偏转器  - 是的，长官
- Prepare to activate deflectors. - Aye, sir.
动力下降，长官
Power dropping, sir.
轮机手，保持全功率，全功率
Engineering, maintain full power. Full power.
我们必须更换二锂晶体
We must replace the dilithium crystal.
- 现在不行  - 0，偏转点...现在，长官
- Not now. - Zero. Deflection point... now, sir.
启动偏转器
Activate deflectors.
动力下降，长官
Power dropping, sir.
偏转角度，苏鲁先生
Degree of deflection, Mr. Sulu.
还不够，长官，只有0.0013度
Not enough, sir. It's only 0.0013 degrees.
为引擎提供再循环动力，最大速度，航向37，标记010
Recircuit power to engines. Maximum speed, heading 37, mark 010.
- 这将使我们进入小行星的路径  - 我们将在那颗小行星前面撤退
- That will put us in the asteroid's path. - We'll retreat in front of that asteroid
直到我们能把所有动力部署在相位炮上
until we can employ all power on phasers.
- 为了什么？- 摧毁它
- What for? - To destroy it.
在一个单点上的窄光束将分裂该质量
A narrow beam on a single spot will split that mass.
也可能使船瘫痪，然后我们被压碎
It might also cripple the ship, and we'd be crushed.
我们将利用脉冲动力脱离它的轨道
We'll get out of its path by use of impulse power.
吉姆将无法从它的轨道脱身
Jim won't be able to get out of its path.
这是我们必须承担的另一个风险
That is another risk we must take.
米拉曼尼
Miramanee.
- 你在做什么？- 我必须满足神的需要
- What are you doing? - I must see to the needs of the god.
你应该在做我们的仪式斗篷
You should be working on our ritual cloak.
现在我们之间不再有仪式了
There will be no ritual between us now.
什么？我们不能违背传统
What? We cannot go against tradition.
正是因为传统，我不能嫁给你
It is because of tradition that I cannot marry you.
但你已经答应我了
But you are promised to me.
那是在他来之前
That was before he came.
部落女祭司和首席医师总是结为夫妻
Tribal priestess and medicine chief are always joined.
他现在是首席医师了
He is medicine chief now.
萨利希，选别人吧，任何少女都会很荣幸与你结为夫妻
Salish, choose another. Any maiden would be honored to join with you.
我不要其他人
I wish no other.
你别无选择
You have no choice.
米拉曼尼，如果你可以选择...
Miramanee, if you could choose...
你会选择我吗？
would you choose me?
也许你现在想洗澡
Perhaps you would like to bathe now.
米拉曼尼...
Miramanee...
跟我说说智者吧
tell me about the Wise Ones.
要我说？神知道一切
Tell? But a god knows everything.
我不知道，告诉我
Not this one. Tell me.
智者从很远的地方把我们带到这里
The Wise Ones brought us here from far away.
他们选择了一位首席医师来保守神殿的秘密
Those chose a medicine chief to keep the secret of the temple
并在天空变暗时使用它
and to use it when the sky darkens.
神殿的秘密
Secrets of the temple.
没有系带，怎么解开？
There are no lacings. How is this removed?
秘密是从父亲传给儿子的？
The secrets were passed on from father to son?
是的，这如何打开的？
Yes. How does this open?
为什么萨利希不使用它？为什么人们处于危险之中？
Why doesn't Salish use it? Why are the people in danger?
他的父亲不想太早分享他的权力
His father did not wish to share his power too soon.
他在告诉萨利希这个秘密之前就死了
He died before he told Salish the secret.
我们的人民欢欣鼓舞，并希望授予你尊称
Our people rejoice, and wish to honor your name.
但我不知道你希望别人怎么称呼你
But I did not know what you wished to be called.
我该怎么和他们说？
What may I tell them?
柯...
Ki...
柯尔...
Kir...
柯洛克？
Kirok?
- 我们让你不高兴吗？- 不，一切都很好
- Have we displeased you? - No. Everything is fine.
那么一定是我们自己，我们生活的方式
Then it must be ourselves, the way we live.
也许我们没有像智者所希望的那样迅速地进步
Perhaps we have not improved as quickly as the Wise Ones wish.
你们的土地是富饶的，你们的人民是幸福的
Your land is rich, your people happy.
谁会对此感到不满呢？
Who could be displeased with that?
但还有一些东西，告诉我们
But there is something. Tell us.
我们将改变它
We will change it.
我不能告诉你任何事
I can't tell you anything.
我只能告诉你
All I can tell you is that
我在这里很快乐，很平静
I'm happy and peaceful here.
我不确定，但我想我从来没有这种感觉
I'm not sure, but I think I've never felt that way before.
为什么他们如此肯定我能帮助他们？
Why are they so sure I can help them?
你来自石头金属
You came from the stone metal.
- 你没有救那个孩子吗？- 救了，但是...
- And did you not bring life to the child? - Yes, but...
我需要时间来回忆
I need time to remember.
这里有很多时间
Here there is much time.
给任何事
For everything.
- 坐标，契科夫先生  - Tau 8.7，Beta 0.041
- Coordinates, Mr. Chekov. - Tau 8.7, Beta 0.041.
这是我们的目标，小行星最薄弱的点
That is our target. The asteroid's weakest point.
几乎正中心，长官
Almost dead center, sir.
把所有相位炮锁定在那个标记，最大强度
Lock all phasers on that mark. Maximum intensity.
- 我想劈开这个裂缝  - 就好像你在切割一颗钻石
- I want to split that fissure. - It's like you're cutting a diamond.
- 非常贴切，医生  - 所有相位器锁定
- Very astute, Doctor. - All phasers locked.
只要斯科特先生能够保持动力，我们就按顺序发射
We'll fire in sequence as long as Mr. Scott can maintain power.
- 准备好了，长官  - 发射相位炮
- Standing by, sir. - Fire phasers.
相位炮1发射
Phaser 1 firing.
直到这些东西变成一滩铅水，他才会满意
He won't be satisfied till these are a puddle of lead.
苏鲁：相位炮2发射
SULU: Phaser 2 firing.
主继电器再次熄灭
Main relay's out again.
相位炮4发射
Phaser 4 firing.
- 所有相位炮都已发射  - 用于同时射击的钻机
- All phasers fired. - Rig for simultaneous firing.
准备同时发射
Commence simultaneous bombardment.
我的孩子! 我可怜的孩子！
My bairns! My poor bairns!
[脚步声]
[FOOTSTEPS]
仪式斗篷完成了
The ritual cloak is finished.
- 我想确定婚礼日期  - 婚礼日期？
- I would like to name the Joining day. - The Joining day?
我是酋长的女儿，部落法律把我许配给了我们的领袖
I'm the daughter of the chief. Tribal law betroths me to our leader.
如果有别人，我会退出
If there is another, I will step aside.
不，在我心中没有其他人
No, there is no one else in my mind or my heart.
神的愿望凌驾于部落律法之上
God's wish is above tribal law.
确定婚礼日期吧
Name the Joining day.
我们的幸福开始得越早，持续的时间就越长。
The sooner our happiness together begins, the longer it will last.
- 明天  - 明天
- Tomorrow. - Tomorrow.
斯科提：别再要求曲速9的速度了
SCOTTY: And don't ask for any more warp 9 speeds.
我们的星际推进器烧毁了，我们只剩脉冲动力了
Our star drive is burnt out. All we have left is impulse power.
- 预计维修时间  - 像这样漂在太空中？永远
- Estimated repair time. - Hanging here in space? For ever.
唯一能修复这些宝贝的是维修基地
The only thing that will fix these darlings is a repair base.
我已经猜到了，谢谢，斯科特先生
I've already surmised that. Thank you, Mr. Scott.
你以为在瓦肯式的精确权衡下值得冒这个险，但你输了
You took your calculated risk in your calculated Vulcan way and you lost.
对我们，对那颗星球，对吉姆，你都输了
You lost for us, you lost for that planet, and you lost for Jim.
- 我承担责任  - 我职责是保护船员的健康
- I accept the responsibility. - My responsibility is the crew's health.
我想让你休息一下
I want you to get some rest.
契科夫先生，继续航向883，标记41
Mr. Chekov, resume heading 883, mark 41.
回那个星球？这需要几个月的时间
Back to that planet? It'll take months.
正好59.223天，医生
Exactly 59.223 days, Doctor.
这颗小行星将一直落后我们四个小时
And that asteroid will be four hours behind us all the way.
那有什么用呢？
Then what's the use?
即使舰长还活着，我们也可能救不了他
We might not be able to save the captain even if he still is alive.
我们可能救不了任何东西，包括这艘船
We might not be able to save anything, including this ship.
你根本没有听我刚刚说的话
You haven't heard a word I've said.
你一直盯着那座被炸毁的方尖碑
You've just been staring at that blasted obelisk.
另一个精心计算的瓦肯式冒险，医生
Another calculated Vulcan risk, Doctor.
这场婚礼代表着黑暗的终结
This Joining means the end of darkness.
这是我们所有人的欢乐时光
It's a time for joy for all my people.
你等着我先走圣道到达大地小屋
You will wait until I walk the holy path to the earth lodge first,
给我时间告诉女祭司你跟着
to give me time to tell the priestess that you follow,
然后婚礼举行
and that the Joining will take place.
柯克：我找到了天堂
KIRK: I have found paradise.
当然，从来没有人获得过这样的幸福
Surely no man has ever attained such happiness.
- 别挡我的路，萨利希  - 柯洛克，我不同意这场婚礼
- Get out of my way, Salish. - Kirok, I cannot permit this Joining.
- 我们不需要你的同意  - 那就打死我
- We don't need your permission. - Then strike me dead.
我无意打死你
I have no intention of striking you dead.
萨利什： 你流血了！
SALISH: You bleed!
你流血了，柯洛克！
You bleed, Kirok!
看哪，一个流血的神！
Behold a god who bleeds!
看哪，有个流血的神
Behold a god who bleeds.
杀了我，杀了我，柯洛克
Kill me. Kill me, Kirok.
我绝不罢休，直到我向我的子民证明你不是神
For I will not rest until I prove to my people that you are no god.
- 不到医务室报告？- 我必须破译方尖碑符号
- Not reporting to Sickbay? - I must decipher the obelisk symbols.
他们是先进的密码文字
They're advanced cipher writing.
从我们回来开始，你就一直在努力做这件事
You've been trying to do that since we started back.
我知道，当我们到达那颗星球时
I'm aware of that. And when we arrive at the planet
我们只有不到四个小时的时间来实施救援
we'll have barely four hours to effect rescue.
- 这些符号是关键  - 你死也不会读懂它们
- Those symbols are the key. - You won't read them by dying.
你已经几周没有吃东西或睡觉了，你会崩溃的
You've hardly eaten or slept for weeks. You'll collapse.
我不饿，医生
I am not hungry, Doctor.
在压力下，我们瓦肯人可以连续几周不睡觉
And under stress, we Vulcans can do without sleep for weeks.
你的新陈代谢低到几乎测不到了
Your metabolism is so low it can hardly be measured
还有你称之为血液的绿色水...
and that green water you call blood...
我的身体状况并不重要，那座方尖碑才重要
My physical condition is not important. That obelisk is.
我的诊断是过度工作和内疚导致的疲劳
My diagnosis is exhaustion, brought on from overwork and guilt.
你在责怪自己弄坏了这艘船
You're blaming yourself for crippling this ship.
你错了，你做出了命令决定，换成吉姆也会这么做
You're wrong. You made a command decision. Jim would have done it, too.
我的处方是休息，要我让警卫来强制执行吗？
My prescription is rest. Do I have to call security to reinforce it?
米拉曼尼？
Miramanee?
过来这里！
Come here!
米拉曼尼？
Miramanee?
每次你抱着我，都像第一次一样快乐
Each time you hold me is as joyous as the first.
我很高兴，我真高兴
I'm happy. I'm so happy.
如果不是那些梦，我的心会完全平静下来
If it weren't for the dreams, my mind would be completely at peace.
我以为你不再做那些梦了
I thought you no longer had the dreams,
不再看到那些在天空中穿梭的小屋了
that you no longer saw the lodge which moves through the sky.
他们回来了
They've come back.
他们...他们消失了一段时间，但他们回来了
They... were gone for a while, but they've come back.
而我...还看到了一些面孔
And I... see faces, too.
非常模糊
Very dim.
我觉得...我-我应该认识...认识他们
I feel... I-I should know... know them.
我觉得我应该和他们在一起
I feel my place is with them.
不在这里
Not here.
我不配拥有这种幸福
I don't deserve this happiness.
我有一份礼物给你
I have a gift for you.
礼物？
A gift?
- 什么？  - 它可能会让你快乐
- What? - It may make you happy.
等等
Wait.
柯克：在过去的几周里，我对米拉曼尼的爱与日俱增
KIRK: These last few weeks, my love for Miramanee grows stronger each day.
然而，梦境每晚都会回来
However, the dreams return every night.
记忆的碎片...我几乎可以抓住他们
Fragments of memories... I can almost get hold of them,
然后，
and then...
我怀了你的孩子
I bear your child.
你！
You!
一条灌溉渠，有了它我们能把湖水...
A canal. And with it we'll bring the water from the lake...
直接引到小屋
right to the lodge.
我们可以扩展系统
And we can expand the system
灌溉田地，使粮食供应增加一倍
and irrigate the fields, and double the food supply.
并且...有了灯的帮助
And... with the power of the lamp,
把黑夜变成白昼
which turns night into day,
我们可以煮两倍的食物，正如你教给我们的，保...
we can cook twice as much food and, as you taught us, pre...
- 保存  - 保存
- Preserve. - Preserve.
- 保存  - 为饥荒时期
- Preserve. - For times of famine.
这就是你制作这盏灯的原因
That is why you made the lamp.
- 这样我就可以永远做饭了  - 哦，不
- So that I would be forever cooking. - Oh, no.
让你永远做饭根本不是我做这盏灯的原因
That's not why I made the lamp at all, to keep you forever cooking.
[雷球]
[THUNDERCRACK]
只是风和雷声
It's only the wind and the thunder.
我表现得像个傻孩子，我没什么好怕的，你在这里
I act like a stupid child. I have nothing to fear. You are here.
- 是时候了  - 时候？
- It is time. - Time?
去神殿救人
To go to the temple to save the people.
但风不能伤害他们
But the wind can't harm them.
风只是开始，很快，天空就会变暗
The wind is only the beginning. Soon the sky will darken.
湖水会变得狂野，大地会颤抖，只有你能拯救我们
The lake will go wild and the earth will tremble. Only you can save us.
但是我对风或天空无能为力
But I can't do anything about the wind or the sky.
如果我们现在不去，那就太晚了
If we do not go now, it will be too late.
你必须让蓝色的火焰从神殿里出来
You must make the blue flame come out of the temple.
我...不知道如何进入神殿
I... don't know how to get inside the temple.
但你是神
But you are a god.
萨利希：柯洛克！柯洛克！
SALISH: Kirok! Kirok!
你为什么不在神殿里？很快，地面就会颤抖
Why are you not at the temple? Soon the ground will tremble.
人们需要你的帮助
The people need your help.
我们去洞穴，那里会很安全
We'll go to the caves. It will be safe there.
洞穴？当然，一个传奇人物可以为他的人民做得更多
The caves? Surely a legend can do more than that for his people.
当地面颤抖时，洞穴就不安全了
When the ground trembles, the caves are not safe.
如果你不唤醒神殿精神，我们都会死！
If you do not rouse the temple spirit, we will all die!
没有什么是你做不到的，我的丈夫
There is nothing you cannot do, my husband.
神啊，你还在等什么呢？你的长袍？
What do you wait for, god? Your robes?
照顾好米拉曼尼
Take care of Miramanee.
我是柯洛克！
I am Kirok!
我来了！我是柯洛克！
I have come! I am Kirok!
- 我开了睡眠处方  - 你开了休息处方
- I prescribed sleep. - You prescribed rest.
方尖碑上的符号是音符
The symbols on the obelisk are musical notes.
你的意思是它只不过是一首歌？
You mean it's nothing but a song?
在某种程度上，其他文化，其中包括某些瓦肯人的分支
In a way. Other cultures, among them certain Vulcan offshoots,
使用音符作为单词
use musical notes as words.
音调对应于字母表
The tones correspond to an alphabet.
- 你弄明白了吗？  - 方尖碑是一个标记，正如我所想的那样
- Did you make any sense of it? - The obelisk is a marker as I thought.
它被一个被称为"保护者"的超级种族所留下
It was left by a super race known as the Preservers.
他们拯救了濒临灭绝的原始文化
They rescued primitive cultures which were in danger of extinction
并把它们播种在可以生活和生长的地方
and seeded them where they could live and grow.
我想知道为什么有这么多人形生物
I wondered why there were so many humanoids.
显然，保护者占其中的一部分
Apparently the Preservers account for a number of them.
这可能就是这个星球幸存下来的方式
That's probably how the planet has survived.
- 他们在那里放了一个小行星偏转器  - 现在无法运行
- They put an asteroid deflector there. - Which is now failing to operate.
我们必须找到偏转器并修复它
And we have to find the deflector and fix it.
- 否则...   - 没错，医生
- Otherwise... - Precisely, Doctor.
那个是假的！
There's the false one!
去死！去死！
Die! Die!
不！不！别伤害他！
No! No! Don't hurt him!
- 米拉曼尼！- 不要伤害他！
- Miramanee! - Don't hurt him!
- 回去！- 他是假的！
- Go back! - He's false!
- 我属于他  - 那就走
- I belong to him. - Then go.
和你的假神一起去死！
Die with your false god!
你会被杀死的！
You'll be killed!
杀了他！
Kill him!
去死，冒牌货！
Die, impostor!
- 你骗了我们！- 杀了他！
- You lied to us! - Kill him!
我需要查佩尔护士
I need Nurse Chapel.
- 史波克呼叫企业号  - 斯科提[通过无线电]：请回答
- Spock to Enterprise. - SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: Come in.
把查佩尔护士和应急手术包传送下来
Beam down Nurse Chapel with an emergency surgical kit.
我妻子，她没事吧？
My wife. Is she all right?
妻子？幻觉？
Wife? Hallucinations?
米拉曼尼
Miramanee.
护士给了你一些东西来缓解疼痛
The nurse has given you something to ease the pain.
你为什么被人用石头砸？
Why were you being stoned?
柯洛克无法回到...神殿
Kirok could not get back into the... temple.
当然，因为他不是从那里来的
Naturally, since he did not come from there.
我看到他来...来的
I saw him come... come...
他认出我们了吗？
Does he recognize us?
一切运作正常，除了他的记忆
Everything is functioning normally except his memory.
帮助他需要时间
It would take time to help him.
时间是唯一我们没有的东西
Time is the one thing we do not have in abundance.
[通讯器哔哔声]
[COMMUNICATOR BLEEPS]
- 我是史波克  - 苏鲁[通过无线电]：路径报告
- Spock here. - SULU [OVER RADIO]: Tracking report.
65分钟后到达安全边界
65 minutes to end of safety margin.
报告已知悉
Report noted.
他是否强壮到可以进行瓦肯心灵融合？
Is he strong enough for Vulcan mind-fusion?
我们别无选择
We have no choice.
我是史波克
I am Spock.
你是詹姆斯·柯克
You are James Kirk.
我们的意识正在接近
Our minds are moving closer.
再近点，再近点，再近点，詹姆斯·柯克
Closer, closer, closer, James Kirk.
再近一点
Closer.
不！
No!
- 詹姆斯·柯克  - 米拉曼尼！
- James Kirk. - Miramanee!
不！米拉曼尼！
No! Miramanee!
我们的意识...是一体的
Our minds... are one.
- 我...是...柯洛克  - 柯洛克！
- I... am... Kirok. - Kirok!
两者：我...是...柯洛克！
BOTH: I... am... Kirok!
我是柯...
I am Ki...
我...我是柯洛克！
I... I'm Kirok!
- 我是... - 史波克！
- I am... - Spock!
- 这是什么？- 他的意识
- What is it? - His mind.
他是...一个非常有活力的人
He's... an extremely dynamic individual.
成功了
It worked.
舰长，你在这个建筑物里面吗？
Captain, were you inside this structure?
是的，里面装满了科学设备
Yes. What's inside is loaded with scientific equipment.
方尖碑是一个偏转装置，我们必须立即进入
The obelisk is a deflector mechanism. We must get inside immediately.
舰长，我们没有太多时间
Captain, we do not have much time.
麦考伊
McCoy.
- 我不知道怎么进去  - 如果我们不激活这个装置
- I don't know how to get inside. - If we do not activate the mechanism,
整个星球将被摧毁
this entire planet will be destroyed.
答案一定在这些符号中，我们必须破译它们
The key must be in the symbols. We must decipher them.
在某种程度上，我有，它们是音符
I have, to some extent. They are musical notes.
演奏乐器可以获得入场券吗
Entry can be gained by playing an instrument?
这将是一种方法，另一种是一系列的音调特征
That would be one method. Another would be a series of tonal qualities.
把你的通讯器给我
Give me your communicator.
我一定是在联系飞船时不小心猜到了
I must have hit it accidentally when I contacted the ship.
如果你能记得你的原话，舰长...
If you can remember your exact words, Captain...
- 柯克呼叫企业号  - 斯科提[通过无线电]：是的，舰长
- Kirk to Enterprise . - SCOTTY [OVER RADIO]: Aye, Captain.
如果偏转器在 20 分钟内未激活
If the deflector isn't activated within 20 minutes,
让企业号离开危险区域
get the Enterprise out of the danger zone.
登陆小队可以牺牲，企业号不能
The landing party is expendable. The Enterprise isn't.
柯克完毕
Kirk out.
米拉曼尼
Miramanee.
老骨头，陪着她
Bones, stay with her.
尽你所能
Do what you can.
它类似于我见过的面板，但要复杂得多
It is similar to panels I've seen, but far more complicated.
小心，我一定是不小心撞到了什么东西
Careful. I must have hit something accidentally.
一道光束抓住了我，就在那时我停止了记忆
A beam caught me and that's when I stopped remembering.
可能是记忆光束，您必须按顺序激活它
Probably a memory beam. You must have activated it out of sequence.
- 更多符号，你能读懂它们吗？  - 我确实对音乐有很好的眼光
- More symbols. Can you read them? - I do have an excellent eye for music.
它们表明，这一系列的继电器在...
They indicate that this series of relays, activated in...
史波克，按右边的按钮
Spock, just press the right button.
- 她怎么样？- 她内伤严重，吉姆
- How is she? - She had bad internal injuries, Jim.
她会活下去吗？
Will she live?
不
No.
柯洛克，这是真的，你是安全的
Kirok. It is true. You are safe.
你们的人们也是如此
And so are your people.
我知道你会救他们的，我的首席医师
I knew you would save them, my chief.
当我好转时
When I am better,
它会像以前一样，不是吗？
it will be as it was, will it not?
如果这是你想要的
If that's what you want.
我们将过上长寿和幸福的生活
We will live long and happy lives.
我要给你生许多强壮的儿子[呻吟]
I will bear you many strong sons. [MOANS]
我会永远爱你
I'll love you always.
我会爱你的，米拉曼尼
And I'll love you, Miramanee.
永远
Always.
每个吻都像第一次
Each kiss is as the first.